I don't care how
much they offered you.
We're not selling till
the season's over, okay?
Twenty grand, Keith.
Twenty grand for
an unproven colt.
Look, he's
Mr. Moonshine's full brother.
If Mr. Moonshine keeps winning,
that yearling out there's gonna
be worth 40 grand, trust me.
I know you like to bet, but
what if he doesn't keep winning?
I don't have the stomach
for gambling that you do.
That's what makes us a good
team. Your brains, my guts.
So, uh, what happened
to Royal T last week?
- She didn't even place.
- The other jockey boxed her in.
Don't worry, it
won't happen again.
I fired him.
See you.
Hey, old Whiz Kid here looked
pretty good today, don't you think?
Yeah, looked great.
Yeah, think it's time we
got him to Redway Downs,
got him some real track work.
Whatever you say. That's
why we're paying you big bucks.
Janice back yet?
Coming in right now.
Hi.
I had a great ride. You
should have come with me.
Where's Keith?
- Didn't you ask him for dinner?
- He had plans.
- What's wrong?
- We got another letter.
So who am I supposed
to be sleeping with now?
It doesn't say.
So, what else is new?
This one says you were with someone
the night I was in Savannah last week.
- And you believe it?
- I tried to call you that night
but you weren't home.
I told you already, I went to dinner
and a movie with Melissa that night.
Then you went for a drive,
didn't get home till after 1.
- What am I supposed to believe?
- I don't give a damn what you believe.
They don't mean anything?
Who's sending these?
Why would they send them?
I don't know who's sending them.
Janice, I love you, but you
are making it very difficult.
I'm really hurt that you
believe some crackpot,
who won't even sign his
name, instead of your own wife.
I tried to call yesterday
and you weren't home either.
Stop it, Mike.
This jealously thing has gotta
stop. It's gonna destroy us.
Just tell me where you were.
I was out buying your stupid
birthday present, that's where I was.
Janice, I'm sorry.
Oh, just leave me alone.
Mr. Matlock.
Hi.
I'm Mike Wilson and I
need your help. Can we talk?
- You mean now? In here?
- It's kind of urgent.
Well, I have to get
back to a hearing.
Uh, call me at my office.
I'm listed in Willis Spring.
I've been working
out of my house lately,
kind of cut down
on the overhead.
So you just call me
anytime you, uh...
Uh, Mr. Wilson?
Mr. Wilson?
Hi.
How did you get in here?
I know I'm imposing
and I'm sorry.
But like I said before,
this is important.
- How did you get in here?
- The door.
Well, you just go
back out the door.
Listen to me, okay?
You don't understand. You're
the only one who can help me.
- Out.
- My wife is on trial for murder,
only the lawyer she's
got is incompetent.
Well, not incompetent
really, just unqualified.
- See, he's an old family friend.
- Out!
You couldn't have come
in this door, it's bolted.
Maybe the other door.
You gotta talk to
him, advise him,
maybe even take
over the case for him.
The back door's locked too.
Please, you've gotta help me.
Scott Ainsley, that's her
lawyer. Do you know him?
I know of him.
Talk to him about Janice's
case tomorrow morning.
- Talk to him about what?
- His strategy. How he's pleading her.
It's not my place.
I love my wife more than anything,
and her future is at stake here.
And I am gonna do
whatever I have to to help her.
Please, talk to Scott
Ainsley first thing tomorrow.
Out!
Please.
Mr. Ainsley?
Hi, Ben Matlock.
We met at a Georgia State Bar
meeting a couple of years back.
- Right. It's good to see you again.
- Good to see you.
Could I just speak with
you in private, please?
Yes, of course. Um, go on over
to my office. I'll be right there.
- Is that Ms. Wilson?
- Yes.
Well, uh, I don't know whether
her husband said anything to you,
but, uh, he seems to feel
that you might not be...
- Her husband? Mike?
- Yeah.
He came over to my house last
night and he expressed some concern...
He came over to your house?
- Yeah. Yeah. And he said that he...
- Is this some kind of sick joke?
- How's that?
- Mike Wilson is dead.
My client, although she was
temporarily insane at the time,
killed him.
- Say again?
- Mike Wilson is dead.
Mike Wilson's dead?
I have things to
do, Mr. Matlock.
And I should think a man
of your stature does too.
So if there's some kind of punch
line here, could we get to it, please.
Oh, no, there's no punch line.
Mike Wilson's dead.
Mike Wilson is dead.
They think you're dead.
Your wife's on trial
for murdering you.
Why don't you go down to the
police and straighten this thing out.
I am dead.
Sure, and I'm Robert Redford.
Mr. Matlock, somebody
killed me, but it wasn't my wife.
And I'm not gonna let her
go through life thinking it was.
You need professional help.
Look, I know this is odd
but you've gotta believe me.
What are you doing?
Your car's over there.
I know. I'm going across the
street and talk to my friend Pete.
I'm gonna have you arrested.
Maybe they'll commit you.
Wait.
I don't know what I
am, okay? Alive. Dead.
It's been a month and I haven't
been able to figure it out myself.
All of sudden, I'm
in contact with you.
You're the only one who
can see me or hear me.
Hey, Pete.
I guess the only thing
to do is to show you.
Look out!
Get out of the way!
You see?
- Ben?
- Get away from me. Leave me alone.
- Get away from me.
Get away. Get away.
Get away.
- Leave me alone. MIKE:
You've gotta help me.
She didn't do it.
Maybe it's something I ate.
There's got to be some
rational explanation.
This can't be happening.
Then why not help me?
I mean, if this is all just a
big dream, what's the harm?
- You are a ghost.
- Of course.
I'm talking to a ghost.
- You're a ghost?
- Yes.
- It's not possible.
- Yes, it is.
- I can do more tricks for you.
- No.
What were you and your wife
arguing about that afternoon?
Oh, I don't know. We were
newlyweds. We argued.
The only important thing
is that she pushed me
and then she ran out of
the barn. Now, she thinks
that my head hit the
shovel when I fell and I died.
The truth is, someone
came in after she left
and used that
shovel to murder me.
And you don't know who.
I heard a noise, started
to look up, and wham!
The next thing I know, I'm standing
there looking down at a body. Mine.
Oh my.
Oh my. I just...
I just don't know.
It wouldn't hurt to
go talk to my wife.
Okay.
Yes.
Yes? MATLOCK: Yes.
I'm Ben Matlock, a lawyer.
Isn't she beautiful?
I wonder if I could talk with you
for a minute about your case?
Oh, I already have a lawyer.
Well, yes, I know. It's just that,
um, Mike was a kind of friend of mine.
Tell her we met
through Uncle Russ
when you did legal work
for him back in Savannah.
I met him in Savannah
while I was doing legal
work for his Uncle Russ.
- Uncle Russ? Heh, what a character.
- Heh, oh, he's a fine man.
He passed away last year.
Was a fine man. Was.
Come on in.
Have a seat.
- Can I get you something to drink?
- No, thanks.
So?
So.
Scott Ainsley's your attorney? I
didn't know he practiced criminal law.
He handled my
husband's business affairs
and my case seemed so
cut-and-dry. I mean, I know I killed Mike.
That's why he pleaded you
innocent by reason of insanity?
Scott figured I might only get a
couple of months in an institution.
You think we did
the wrong thing?
I don't know enough
about the case to say.
Um...
That argument, uh, you had with
Mike outside the stable that day,
- what was that about?
- Uh-oh.
Mike had been getting
these anonymous letters
saying that I was
cheating on him.
Well, everything's
under control.
It doesn't look like she's gonna
foal until morning. So, I, uh...
- Hi. How are you doing?
- Ben Matlock, this is Keith Garrick.
Keith was Mike's
business partner.
- How are you?
- Nice to meet you.
- He's been incredibly supportive
through this whole thing.
Get your hands off her.
Don't know what I
would've done without him.
I hope I'm not interrupting.
- You wanted her all along.
- Go back outside.
- Mr. Matlock.
- That's all right. I'll leave.
I wasn't talking to you.
You weren't? MATLOCK: No. No.
I mean, well, yes, but I
didn't mean it that way.
You wrote those letters.
You were trying to break
us up so you could have her.
- Are you all right?
- Punch him for me.
No.
I mean, no, I'm not all right.
To tell you the truth, I'd better go.
Just one punch. Please, Ben.
Just one punch. Come on.
Come on. He won't hit you
back. You're older than he is.
I'll be back when he...
When I'm feeling better.
What was that all about?
- I have no idea.
- Heh.
Do you wanna get
something to eat?
- Sure.
- Okay.
Oh, Janice.
- So?
- Aah!
Keith is the one who killed
me. I'll bet you anything.
I'm going to bed.
Can't you leave me alone?
You said you'd help
me with the case.
I changed my mind.
- Why?
- I'll tell you why.
As insane as it may be, I
accept the fact that you're a ghost.
But you're the most annoying,
ill-mannered ghost I ever heard of.
Now, please get out of my room.
Hi.
Leave me alone.
Sorry. I can't leave you alone.
- Go away.
- Nope.
- I can't.
- I can.
Get off my TV!
Can we talk?
You lied to me about the
argument you had with Janice.
I was embarrassed.
I'm sorry.
How do you do that?
I don't know.
Here's the deal.
If I'm gonna help, you
have to behave yourself.
And you have to tell me
the truth about Janice.
Like she said, I've been
getting these anonymous letters
saying that she'd been
seeing somebody else.
That's what we were arguing about
that day. I had just gotten another one.
- She denied it?
- Yeah.
You didn't believe her?
As you might have noticed, I
have this little jealousy problem.
Yeah.
I figure somewhere along the
line, Keith fell in love with my wife.
He sent those letters knowing
how nuts it would make me
and that it was only a matter of
time until Janice left me, as a result.
Yeah.
Only, he got impatient. So
he doubled back that day,
waited for her
to leave the barn,
then killed me so that he could
finally have her all to himself.
You still have the letters?
They're in my office at home.
If we can trace
them back to Keith,
they might prove
that he's the real killer.
I think I'll have
Conrad look around.
Thanks for helping me, Ben.
It's okay.
- You wanna get off my bed?
- Oh, sure.
How about out of my room?
See you in the morning.
You make sure
she's good and dry.
Take her in, give her a
good rubdown, turn her out.
By that time, Speed
Sensation over here
will be ready for
the same treatment.
Gotcha.
You do all that as well as you
handle this horse, you've got a job.
Great.
Is Mr. Garrick around?
He's over by the barn.
You know him?
Well, no, I just figured
I'd introduce myself.
I mean, he's one
of the owners, right?
Sucking up to the man
who writes the checks?
It never hurts.
You were supposed to
be here 45 minutes ago.
I don't want anyone
to see. Come on.
You wanted a few
weeks to think it over,
I gave you a few weeks.
Now, what's the answer?
You and your pal in or out?
If anyone found out, you'd
be barred from racing for life.
You own a trotter. It's
odds on to win this Sunday.
Now a man could make
some serious money
knowing she'd lose.
Fix it for me and I'll forget
that 200 grand you owe me.
Mr. Petrie, you just can't...
I guess that I'm not
making myself clear. Timmy.
Make things clear
to Mr. Garrick.
Uh, it's just a horse.
Forget it.
I want your answer tomorrow.
Good girl.
What did you find out?
Keith Garrick's got
some serious problems.
- He's into loan sharks for $200,000.
- I knew it was him.
Almost got my head
handed to me out there.
If it wasn't for
a fidgety horse,
some very big guys would've
found me hiding in that barn.
I made the horse sneeze.
Lunch is ready.
Now, listen.
Let's go out to the
farm and nail this sucker.
After I eat.
He's in love with Janice,
up to his neck in debt.
- What more do you need?
- I just... Food, now.
Behave yourself, okay?
Ohh.
Turkey on rye with cranberry
sauce. I could eat five of them.
Conrad, you want a turkey
on rye with cranberry sauce?
How did you know?
It was a lucky guess.
Uh, we have to figure out
where Keith Garrick went
when he left Mike Wilson's
farm after the murder.
Does he have an alibi or
could he have doubled back
and gone into the stable
after Janice Wilson left?
You know, Dad, Conrad
and I are just a little confused.
I mean, Janice Wilson
already has an attorney,
and she more or less
admitted to killing her husband.
Well, she... She thinks she killed
him, but, uh, somebody else did.
Oh. How do you know?
There was a witness.
Oh, yeah?
How come he hasn't come forward?
Well, he's, um, out of
town, kind of permanently.
Are you saying he
refuses to testify?
No, I'm saying he can't.
Leanne, you really
wouldn't understand.
Dad, why don't you try me?
Okay.
Uh...
I may be a little...
eccentric, but I am rational.
Yeah.
I mean, I don't drink a lot
and no drugs, no hallucination.
Dad, what are you getting at?
Well, the reason I'm getting
involved in the Wilson case is
Mike Wilson wants me to.
Mike Wilson?
The victim?
The dead victim?
Yeah.
He's sitting beside
me right now.
You're telling me you
see someone in that chair?
Yeah.
And you talk to him?
Oh, and that's why
we're on the case?
- Yeah.
- Heh.
You know, Dad, you haven't
been sleeping well lately.
- Yeah. LEANNE:
You just mentioned that
the other day.
So I tell you what you're
gonna do. Just relax,
take a couple of days off.
Conrad and I are on it now.
No.
I'll handle it myself.
Dad?
Do you think my
father is... Nuts?
I sure am glad I told Conrad
and Leanne about you.
Hmm, sorry that didn't work out.
They think I'm crazy.
Who's that?
Stuart Cokely, our trainer.
The man's been working
on that trailer for months.
Stay here.
I mean it.
Go on back there
or I'm going home.
Okay.
- Hi.
- Can I help you?
- Yeah.
I'm Ben Matlock, lawyer. I'm
kind of helping out on the case.
Is Janice home?
Uh, left about a half hour
ago. Had to be in court.
Doggone.
She said she was gonna leave
something for me in the house.
Do you suppose it's open?
- You can try it.
- Yeah. Yeah.
Well, that was a terrible thing
that happened to Mike, wasn't it?
Yeah.
Were you here that day?
Yeah. I was turning out some
horses and I heard Mrs. Wilson scream.
And like you said, it
was a terrible thing.
I'll say it was.
I understand that Keith
Garrick was here that afternoon.
Yeah. He'd just left.
So he wasn't one of them that
came running into the stable
after Janice found the body?
Nope. Long gone.
- Thanks for your time, heh.
- It's okay.
I kept the letters locked
up in the desk drawer.
The key's gone.
You'll just have to break in.
They're gone.
Did Janice know where
you kept the letters?
She didn't know I kept
them at all. Nobody did.
- Not even Keith?
- Not even Keith.
Who knew where you
kept the key to the drawer?
Good question.
You wanna go downtown?
- It's not Keith?
- It's Keith.
I think I know how to prove it.
It was Scott Ainsley. He's the only
one who knew where I kept that key.
As Janice's lawyer, I'm
sure she let him in the office
- to go through my papers.
- Well, if he's your lawyer,
I guess he and Keith could
have been up to something.
- Uh-huh.
- Um...
- Go on.
- I'd be breaking and entering.
You're not breaking anything.
Well, I guess I'm
just trespassing.
And in the company of a ghost.
If he did steal those letters,
he probably threw them away
a long time ago and why
would he steal them for Keith?
- Now what?
- Over there.
Open that. The ledger
for the farm is in there.
Scott Ainsley was an accountant?
No, we just kept all
the papers in his office.
Open it to the last entry.
I died before I got a chance to
review the figures for the last quarter.
You think Scott Ainsley
was doctoring the books?
I know he was.
Ben Matlock? What are you doing?
I was just, uh, going over the
ledger for the, uh, Wilson horse farm.
Hi, Mr. Garrick. Do you two
fellows always meet this late at night?
I'm calling the police.
Do that and I'm sure they'd
be as fascinated as I am.
What are you talking about?
Well, for one thing...
Keith's been
embezzling from the farm
and Scott Ainsley's
been helping him.
According to the ledger, uh, Keith
here has been skimming funds,
probably to pay off loan sharks.
And you've been helping
him, for a small fee, no doubt.
My accountant, Dennis Prescott,
should be able to confirm it.
I'm sure that Dennis
Prescott could confirm
that these figures
have been altered.
He sent those letters because
he's in love with Janice.
Excuse me?
I'm saying that the two of you
have been cooking the books,
and successfully,
till times got tough.
And then, uh, when Mike
got worried about money,
you figured you'd better
do something to distract him
and so you sent
him those letters.
And then one or both of you
got afraid that that wasn't enough
and so you killed him.
Now how could you
possibly know that?
What the hell difference does it
make how he knows? He knows.
Uh, you could
kill me too, but...
We may have sent those letters,
Mr. Matlock, but we didn't kill Mike.
As it happens, we have an alibi.
- Shut up.
- No.
If he tells,
it is over.
Look, it's not exactly a
brilliant career move for me.
We don't have a choice.
At the time of the murder?
We were meeting with a
man named Ross Petrie.
He's a local loan shark.
You can ask him or anybody
at that social club he owns.
That's where we met.
You were both there?
God help us, yes.
This has got to work. - Yeah?
You've got to talk Janice
into using you as her lawyer.
I'll do the best I
can. Stay here.
Forget it.
- Mr. Matlock.
- Hi, Ms. Wilson.
I called Aunt Mel, Uncle
Russ' widow in Savannah.
She's never heard
of you, Mr. Matlock.
She said if you did legal
work for Uncle Russ,
she'd know who you were.
Uh, she's right, Ms. Wilson.
I did lie to you.
I never did any legal
work for your Uncle Russ
and I didn't know your
husband 10 years ago.
Why? Why did you lie?
Why are you here?
Have you ever believed
something was wrong and known
- you had to do something about it?
- It doesn't explain why you lied.
Uh, I wanted to talk
with you, Ms. Wilson.
I might be able to help.
I know that Scott Ainsley
resigned your case this morning
and I thought maybe you
would let me represent you.
Why do you wanna be
involved in my case so badly?
Tell her the truth.
I believe that you're innocent.
And if... If what
I believe is true,
then you shouldn't... You shouldn't
go to jail for something you didn't do.
So, Mrs. Wilson, what
have you got to lose?
Come on, Janice.
I think you're crazy.
But you are right
about one thing.
I have nothing to lose.
Yes!
All right. You did it.
Wanna get to work?
- I'm gonna kill you.
- It's too late.
I say Scott and Keith are lying
about being with Ross Petrie.
Come on, Mike.
If they were lying, they would have
said they were with a priest or a rabbi
or Queen of England,
not some Mob person.
Well, who killed me?
Uh, somebody from
your past, maybe.
I was a nice guy,
Ben. People like me.
Well, there was Mel
Whitaker over in Macon.
He didn't like me a whole
lot. Sold me a bum horse.
There was Harold
Ramsey up in Branderville,
thought I'd sold
him a bum horse.
Branderville? Why does
that sound so familiar?
- What is that smell? MIKE:
Probably horse liniment.
Hmm. Horse liniment?
You know what?
That's what I smelled
in here just before I died.
Horse liniment?
Ben, somebody's watching.
Oh, Mr. Cokely.
Ms. Wilson said that I
could look around in here.
Hey, it's fine by me.
Ben,
something's wrong.
Something's wrong.
His riding boots.
He's not wearing riding boots.
That's what's wrong.
Benjamin Matlock for
the defense, Your Honor.
At the defendant's request,
I have replaced Mr. Ainsley.
Very well. If you're ready to
proceed, by all means, go ahead.
Yes, sir. Defense calls
Stuart Cokely to the stand.
You're toast, pal.
Where are you from?
Branderville, Kentucky.
That's right. That's right. I saw that
name on your license plate frame
on the back of your
horse trailer. Yeah.
Uh, is the name, uh...
Does the name Harold
Ramsey mean anything to you?
That's my stepfather's name.
- Is he deceased?
- Yes.
How did he die?
He committed suicide
about four years ago.
You loved your stepfather
very much, didn't you?
Loved him a lot more than I
loved my real father, that's for sure.
What did he do for a living?
Raised racehorses.
Taught me everything I know.
Three months before he died,
he purchased a champion racehorse
by the name of Workmen's Way.
Planned to put him out to stud.
Paid a million dollars for him.
- Is that right? STUART:
Yes, that's right.
Well, what happened
to Workmen's Way?
Well, about two weeks
after we got him, he died.
Turns out he had
some rare disease.
Any insurance?
No. My father... My stepfather
hadn't quite gotten around to that yet.
So when that horse died,
your stepfather lost everything.
His horses, his farm,
his savings, everything.
- Didn't he?
- Yes.
Within three months, he was
penniless and that's why he killed himself.
Yeah.
Who sold that horse
to your stepfather?
Mike Wilson.
And your stepfather,
Harold Ramsey,
was convinced that Mike Wilson
knew that that horse was sick
- when he sold it to you.
- Yes.
Then, when in despair
he killed himself,
you in turn blamed Mike
Wilson for his death, didn't you?
- No.
- Oh, come on, Stuart.
Out of all the horse
farms in the country,
you chose Mike
Wilson's to go to work at.
Is that just a coincidence or did
you choose to go to work there
so you could wait for your opportunity
to avenge your stepfather's death?
Of course not.
Let me just say, uh, with
your permission, Your Honor,
I have it on good authority
that Mike Wilson did not know
that horse was sick when
he sold him to your stepfather.
He was very saddened to
learn of Mr. Ramsey's death.
But anyway, uh, this
picture appeared in the paper
a few days before
Mike was killed.
That's Mike. That's Janice.
That's you, isn't it, Mr. Cokely.
Yeah, that's me.
Those riding boots are kind
of your trademark, aren't they?
They belonged to my stepfather.
No wonder you wear
them all the time.
Or at least you did.
A couple of your coworkers out
at the farm are prepared to testify
that you haven't worn these boots
since the day Mike Wilson was killed.
Why is that?
Just didn't feel like it.
Liar.
These are, uh, the
shoes Mike was wearing
when he was killed. See, there's
a stain up here in the toe area.
See that there?
And these are
the boots Janice was wearing
when she allegedly caused his death.
See? They're stained too.
And these, ugh, are your
boots, aren't they, Mr. Cokely?
The police removed it from
your apartment an hour ago,
with a warrant. But look here,
stain on the toe
of the boot. See?
Stain on the toe
of this boot, too.
Why is that?
I think I know.
There was a bottle
of horse liniment
that got knocked over
during the argument
between Mike and
Janice that day.
It's right here, isn't
it? In the police report.
It says that...
Says it had spilled all over the
straw on the floor next to Mike's body.
That means anybody walking
through that straw would have gotten
a stain on their boots.
And that's what this stain is,
horse liniment.
Strong. So strong, you
can still smell it. Mm.
Smells kind of like aftershave.
These boots meant
a great deal to you.
That's why you kept them
instead of throwing them away.
But you never wore
them again after that day
because you knew
that they proved
that after Janice ran out of
that barn, you went in there
and hit Mike Wilson over
the head with that shovel.
That's how you got these stains.
You killed Mike Wilson,
didn't you, Mr. Cokely?
I'd just as soon not answer
that until I talk to my lawyer.
Yes!
Your Honor, the prosecution
moves that the charges
against the defendant
be dismissed.
So moved. Case dismissed.
Court is adjourned.
Well,
mission accomplished.
Yeah.
I guess so.
See that Janice is
okay, would you?
Tell her I'm sorry
I was jealous.
I really wanted her
to be happy with me.
And now I just want
her to be happy.
I will.
Goodbye, Ben.
Thanks.
Will Mr. Wilson be
joining us for lunch today
or does he have other plans?
Uh, no. No. Mike's gone.
- He is?
- Mm-hm.
Yeah. Apparently, he was allowed
to hang around for awhile after he died
to straighten
things up for his wife
and after he'd done
that, his reprise was over.
Dad, I talked to a couple of people
and here's what they think happened.
You read about Mike's
death in the paper,
and something about
it piqued your interest
in a totally subconscious way.
Leanne, I had never heard
of Mike Wilson before this.
You read about him.
You saw a picture of
him and Stuart Cokely,
and your subconscious
mind repressed it
and invented this ghost
thing as a way of legitimizing
you getting
involved in the case.
My mind is not
playing tricks on me.
The subconscious
is very powerful.
It's the only thing that makes
any sense and you know it.
You could be right,
but you're not.
www.tvsubtitles.net